

CONTACTS

+38 098 461 7282

<u> chornyalexander@gmail.com</u>

www.chorny-alexander/

in <u>Alexander Chorny</u>

Vinnitsa, Ukraine

SKILLS

- HTML / CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React.js
 - Next.js
- Redux
- D3.js
 - APIs
 - AJAX
 - JSON
- Figma, Photoshop
- Git

LANGUAGES

- English Upper-Intermediate
- German Intermediate
- Ukrainian Native
- Russian Native

ALEXANDER CHORNY

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I'm a passionate developer with relevant experience in web development. I focus on creating reliable, adaptive, cross-browser web products, emphasizing best practices and accessibility.

In life, I enjoy self-learning, constantly working on improving my technical and communication skills. I strive to learn something new or accomplish something useful every day.

Additionally, I enjoy sports and pursuing diverse personal development opportunities.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer Apr 2024 - Jul 2024 (Antalya, TR · Remote)

Participated in a project involving the creation and management of databases. Refined the functionality of a code editor based on CodeMirror, implementing combined language support (SQL and JavaScript) with syntax highlighting and autocompletion. Contributed to various other project features.

Skills Used and Improved: React \cdot CodeMirror \cdot TypeScript \cdot JavaScript \cdot Lezer \cdot Recoil \cdot Git \cdot Codespaces \cdot Ant Design.

Freelance Web Developer Jan 2023 - Dec 2023 (Antalya, TR · Remote)

- 1. ONE-OF-PRO (Tech Job Platform) teamwork;
- 2. MYHOBBY-ECOMMERSE (store) I work independently.

Skills Used and Improved: React \cdot Next.js \cdot Docker \cdot TypeScript \cdot GraphQL \cdot MongoDB \cdot Jest \cdot GitHub/Codespaces \cdot GitHub/task-board.

Consultant/Content Manager Jul 2009 - Feb 2022 (Vinnytsia, UA) MYHOBBY

Website maintenance, consultations, sales, purchase of goods.

Improvement Of A Website Apr 2015 - Jun 2015 (Berlin, DE - Remote) APPAREL EXPRESS

Improvement of website design and functionality. Refinement of the order sorting module.

Website Development Dec 2014 - Feb 2015 (Kyiv, UA - Remote) KRAINEVA ANASTASIA

Website development for an artist.

EDUCATION

Data Visualization with D3 Nov 2024 - Dec 2024
Front End Development Libraries Aug 2024 - Nov 2024
JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Nov 2022 - Aug 2024
Responsive Web Design Sep 2022 - Nov 2022
FreeCodeCamp | USA (Remote)

Maintenance of electrical installations Sep 1991 - May 1994 Vocational and Technical Education Center No. 1 | Vinnytsia, UA